Aaa...
tuh...
AT!
Two sounds just became a word.
Today you're going to do that sixteen times.
Blending is easy.
Say the sounds apart...
...then squeeze them together.
Slow first.
Fast after.
Red box is a vowel.
Blue box is a consonant.
When the vowel goes first, we get these.
Aaa...
tuh...
at.
Aaa...
nuh...
an.
Aaa...
mmm...
am.
Ih...
nuh...
in.
Ih...
tuh...
it.
Oh...
ks...
ox.
Uh...
puh...
up.
Uh...
sss...
us.
Eight words.
Vowel first, every time.
Now flip it.
Consonant first.
Buh...
aaa...
ba.
Mmm...
aaa...
ma.
Mmm...
eh...
me.
Wuh...
eh...
we.
Guh...
oh...
go.
Nuh...
oh...
no.
Sss...
ih...
si.
Duh...
oh...
do.
Eight more.
Consonant first, every time.
Here's the secret.
These aren't just little words.
Put a sound in front of them.
At...
buh-aaa-t...
Bat!
An...
fff-aaa-n...
Fan.
Am...
juh-aaa-m...
Jam.
In...
puh-ih-n...
Pin.
It...
sss-ih-t...
Sit.
Ox...
fff-oh-ks...
Fox.
Up...
kuh-uh-p...
Cup.
Us...
buh-uh-s...
Bus.
And the other eight?
Put the sound at the back.
Ba...
buh-aaa-g...
Bag.
Ma...
mmm-aaa-p...
Map.
Me...
mmm-eh-t...
Met.
We...
wuh-eh-t...
Wet.
Go...
guh-oh-t...
Got.
No...
nuh-oh-t...
Not.
Si...
sss-ih-ks...
Six.
Do...
duh-oh-g...
Dog.
You didn't learn sixteen little words.
You learned sixteen word machines.
Blended along with me?
Tap the thumbs up.
I want to know you did it!
Your turn.
Blend it with me.
Aaa...
nuh...?
An!
Duh...
oh...?
Do!
Last one.
Which word is this?
Kuh...
uh...
puh...
Cup!
You blended a whole word by yourself.
Hit subscribe, because next time we blend three sounds.
Cat.
Dog.
Pig.
Blend all sixteen yourself in the English Learning app.
Tap the boxes, hear every sound.
Free on both stores!